[You've enjoyed "Tuesday E-Jump."
But we've come to the final episode.]
[So today, we'll show you a great time until the very end.]
Don't give me that!
(お登勢)ふざけんじゃねえ！
ﾃﾒｴの蛮行によって➡
Do you have any idea what a nuisance your barbarism has become?!
どれだけの人々が苦しんでんのか
わかってんのかぁ!?
(西郷)やかましいわ ｸｿばばあ！
回覧板まわすの 遅れたくらいで➡
Shut up, you old hag!
Where do you get off talking to me like this
なんで そこまで
言われなきゃなんねえんだ！
just because I was late with the neighborhood notice?!
かぶき町は 浄も不浄も混ざった
ﾑﾁｬｸﾁｬな街だからこそ➡
Kabukicho is a place where the pure and the dirty are mixed together.
ﾃﾒｴのﾙｰﾙだけは守って
生きていかなきゃならねえんだ！
That's all the more reason why you have to live according to the rules!
んなこと言って ばばあ
お前 こないだ➡
That's what you say, granny,
but just last week you put out JUMP comics on burnable trash day!
燃えるｺﾞﾐに
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ出してたじゃねえか！
違え！ あれは
２階に住んでるﾔﾂが…！
Not me! That was the guy on the second floor!
(銀時)んだよ うるせえなぁ｡
(西郷)ｱﾝﾀ➡
You're making too much noise...
Don't play dumb!
Don't get carried away because they call you the Empress of Kabukicho!
かぶき町の女帝とか言われて
調子のってんじゃねえの？
おい うるせえんだよ
そこの妖怪２匹｡
Hey, keep it quiet, you two freaks.
今 何時だと思ってんだ｡
Do you have any idea what time it is?
そして ｵﾚの血圧を
いくつだと思ってんだ｡
You're raising my blood pressure.
Shut up, loser!!
うるせえんだよ この ﾀﾞﾒ人間が！
まっとうな人間は
とっくに 活動 始めてんだよ！
Decent human beings have already started their day at this hour!
ｵﾒｴら 自分のこと
人間だと思ってんのか？
You guys think you're "human beings"?
Maybe you were a long time ago.
それは 遠い昔の話だよ｡
おべりばっ!!
ｱﾀｼに たてついたからには
落とし前つけてもらうよ｡
You're going to pay for even thinking you can defy me.
(西郷)ｺｲﾂは預かるからね｡
(お登勢)好きにしな｡
I'm taking him with me.
Go right ahead.
Shinpachi. Who is that monster?
(神楽)新八 あのﾓﾝｽﾀｰ 何ｱﾙ？
(新八)ん？ あぁ…｡
あれは お登勢さんと同じく➡
Like Otose-san, she's one of the Four Royals of Kabukicho...
この街を支える
かぶき町 四天王の１人➡
鬼神… ﾏﾄﾞﾏｰｾﾞﾙ西郷｡
The Demoness Mademoiselle Saigo.
["Cute Faces Are Always Hiding Something"]
Girls, we have someone new for today.
(西郷)みんな～ 今日から
入ってもらうことになった➡
ﾊﾟｰ子ちゃんよ｡
Meet Pako-chan.
Oh my, she's cute.
(ｱｺﾞ美)や～だぁ かわいい～｡
(ｱｺﾞ美)なに？ ﾊﾟｰ子って｡
天然ﾊﾟｰﾏの ﾊﾟｰ子よ｡
Why's she called Pako?
Because she's got naturally wavy hair.
(ﾜｶﾒ)ちょっと ﾏﾏ～ 勘弁してよ｡
私のお客 取られちゃうわ｡
Give me a break, Mama. She's going to steal all of my customers.
すみません
お腹 痛いんで 早退します｡
I'm sorry, I have a stomach ache so I'll be leaving early.
(西郷)逃げられないわよ｡
You can't escape that easily.
かぶき町で生きていくってことが
どういうことか➡
I'll teach you what it means to survive in Kabukicho.
ｱﾝﾀに 教えてやるよ｡
いや もう知ってますから｡
住んでるんで｡
I already know. I live here.
(西郷)ｱﾝﾀが 化け物呼ばわりした
ｱﾀｼたちが➡
I'll teach you the noble way of those you call "freaks."
どれほど気高く生きてるか
教えてやるよ｡
いやぁ ﾎﾝﾄ 勘弁してください｡
一応 ﾎﾞｸ 主人公なん…｡
Really, give me a break. I'm the main character, you know.
(西郷)おりゃあ～っ!!
ぐはぁっ!!
(西郷)新入りに この道の厳しさを
たたきこんでやんな｡
Pound into our new girl how tough it is in this business.
うぅ…｡
なにやってんだ？ ﾂﾞﾗ｡
What're you doing, Zura?
It's not Zura. I'm Zurako.
(桂)ﾂﾞﾗじゃない ﾂﾞﾗ子だ｡
((親父 天そばは まだか？
Pops, isn't our tempura soba ready yet?
(親父)へい 少々 お待ちくだせえ｡
少々だと？
It'll be just a little longer.
A little? Do you know how many instant cup noodles I could've made by now?
これだけ時間があれば ｶｯﾌﾟﾗｰﾒﾝ
何個 作れると思ってるんだ｡
…よせ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
Calm down, Elizabeth.
最近は 不逞浪人に対する取締りも
厳しくなってきている｡
Recently the crackdown on lawless ronin has gotten stricter.
こんなところで
むやみに 目立つﾏﾈをするな｡
Don't do anything that would attract attention to us.
へい お待ち！
…ｷｻﾏ!!
Here you go!
Damn you! Did you forget that we ordered before that guy?!
その者より ｵﾚのほうが 先に
注文 頼んだのを 忘れたのか!!
お侍さま 勘弁してくだせえ｡
この方は 特別な…｡
Please forgive me, mister samurai. This is a special customer...
(桂)いかなる客に対しても➡
It's your duty to treat...
平等に接するのが
ｷｻﾏらの道であろう！
each customer equally!
Prepare to meet your maker!
そこに なおれ！ 成敗してやる!!
ひぃっ！
(西郷)ｲﾔね お客さん➡
Oh come now, mister. Don't get upset over something like this.
こんなことで ﾑｷにならないでよ｡
ほら ｱﾀｼのあげるから｡
Here, you can have mine.
化け物は黙ってろ！
Shut up, freak!
…ぐはぁっ!!
おい 誰が化け物だって？))
Hey. Who're you calling a freak?
…ということだ｡
And that's how I ended up here.
(桂)以来 なんとか抜け出す機会を
うかがっているんだが…｡
Since then, I've been looking for a chance to escape, but...
おい そこ もっと腰振れ！
Hey, you! Sway your hips more.
Zura, you've been here too long.
ﾂﾞﾗ…
長く この空気 吸いすぎたな｡
You might not be able to return to the streets.
お前は ｼｬﾊﾞに戻るのは もうﾑﾘだ｡
ふざけるな｡ ｵﾚには
国を救うという大仕事があるんだ｡
Don't be ridiculous. I have a duty to save my country!
(桂)こんなところで
こんなことしている暇はない｡
I don't have time to waste fooling around here.
こんなところで
ﾉﾘﾉﾘで踊ってるﾔﾂに➡
I don't want my country saved by a guy who dances to the beat of a place like this.
国も 救われたくねえだろうよ｡
(ｱｺﾞ美)ちょっと～
ﾂﾞﾗ子もﾊﾟｰ子も ﾉﾘが悪いわよ｡
Hey, you two.
Zurako, Pako, you're rhythm is off.
Keep dancing like that, and you'll make your customers sick!
そんなんじゃ お客様
気分 悪くしちゃうでしょ｡
なに言ってんのよ｡
What're you talking about? This languid look is my selling point, Agomi.
この けだるさが
私の売りなのよ ｱｺﾞ美｡
Who're you calling Agomi?
(ｱｺﾞ美)誰がｱｺﾞ美だ ｺﾗｧ！
Pako, I told you when I introduced you. This is Agoyo.
ﾊﾟｰ子 さっき紹介しただろ
この人は ｱｺﾞ代だ｡
違うわ！ あずみだ ﾎﾞｹ!!
No, I'm not! It's Azumi. You idiots!
(ﾜｶﾒ)ちょっと ﾊﾟｰ子に ﾂﾞﾗ子
舞台がﾀﾞﾒなら ﾎｰﾙのﾍﾙﾌﾟ お願いよ｡
Come on! Pako, Zurako! If you can't dance, then help out in the hall!
(ｳﾞｧﾈ子)こんにちは ｳﾞｧﾈ子です｡
(ﾜｶﾒ)ﾜｶﾒで～す｡
Good day, I'm Vaneko.
I'm Wakame.
ﾊﾟｰ子で～す｡
ﾂﾞﾗ子です｡
Pako.
Zurako.
(客)おいおい
なんだ お前ら そのﾂﾗは｡
Hey, hey, what's with those faces?
(客)顔で酔わす気か この店は！
Does this place intend to make me drunk with those faces?
That's harsh!
(ｳﾞｧﾈ子)ひっど～い！
(ﾜｶﾒ)超ｼｮｯｸ｡
I'm so shocked...
おい そこの天ﾊﾟｰ
こっちは ﾃﾒｴらみてえな化け物➡
Hey, you with the naturally wavy hair.
I came here to laugh at weirdoes like you!
わざわざ
笑いにきてやってんだからよぉ➡
Do something funny, you freaks!
ﾃﾝｼｮﾝ上げて もっと
ﾊﾞｶなこと やってみせろよ｡
なんだと この すだれじじい｡
ﾃﾒｴの その 残り少ねえ希望を➡
What'd you say, bar code head?
Want me to pull out every last hair of hope on your head?
すべて引き抜いてやろうか？
よせ ﾊﾟｰ子｡
Stop it, Pako.
お客様… ﾎｽﾃｽに触れたり
侮辱したりするのは➡
Sir, I told you touching or insulting the hostesses was forbidden.
禁止と言いましたよね｡
この商売 ﾅﾒんじゃねえ!!
Don't try to make fools out of us!!
がはぁっ!!
(ｱｺﾞ美)女より 気高く
男より たくましく…➡
"More noble than a woman,"
"Stronger than a man..."
それが ﾏﾏの口ぐせ｡
That's Mama's favorite phrase.
People like us need that kind of pride to survive in this world.
私たちみたいな
中途半端な存在は➡
それくらいの気位がないと
世の中 渡っていけない｡
We have to be stronger than anyone or anything.
誰よりも 何よりも
強くなきゃいけないの｡
So are you strong, Agomi?
それじゃ ｱｺﾞ美も強いの？
ｱｺﾞ美のｱｺﾞは 何でも砕ける？
Can that chin of yours break anything?
Why're you limiting her strength to her chin?
(桂)なんで
ｱｺﾞ限定の強さなんだよ｡
それにしても 西郷殿の強さは
常軌を逸しているな｡
But Mademoiselle Saigo's strength is extraordinary.
あれは ただ者ではあるまい｡
He's no ordinary man.
Yes, I hear he used to be amazing back in the day.
えぇ 昔は すごかったらしいわよ｡
なんだっけなぁ… え～と…｡
What was he called...?
(ｱｺﾞ美)白ﾌﾝの西郷だとか
呼ばれてて➡
"White Loincloth Saigo"... or something like that.
なんか よくわかんないけど➡
I don't know what he did, but he was some kind of hero who went into battle wearing a white loincloth.
白いﾌﾝﾄﾞｼ一丁で暴れまわった
豪傑らしいわ｡
いやぁ それだけの情報じゃ
ただの変態じゃねえか！
With only that information, he just sounds like a pervert.
白ﾌﾝの西郷…
どこかで聞いたような…｡
White Loincloth Saigo... I've heard that name somewhere before...
Come on and fight!
(けんちゃん)ｵﾗ
かかってきてみろよ！
Your dad's a guy, but he acts like a mom!
お前の父ちゃん 父ちゃんなのに
母ちゃんじゃねえか！
(よっちゃん)ｺｲﾂも男なのに
娘なんじゃねえの？
Maybe you're a girly boy, too!
That's why he's such a weakling!
だから
こんなに弱っちいんだ… あ？
危険な汁が出てる～！
逃げろ～！
Infectious homo liquid!
Run!
(ｱｺﾞ美)ﾎﾞｸ 大丈夫？
Are you all right, kid?
あっ… て てる君！
Te-Teru-kun!
てる彦～～!!
Teruhiko!
(西郷)何があったの？
こんな大ｹｶﾞして！
What happened?!
You're hurt!
病院よ 早く 病院に行かなきゃ！
赤ひげよ 赤ひげ 呼んで～!!
The hospital! We have to get you to a hospital right away!
Call Dr. Red Beard! Dr. Red Beard!
There are lots of Blue Beards around here.
青ひげなら
いっぱい いますけどね｡
(西郷)ﾃﾒｴらなんざ
お呼びじゃねえんだよ！ 消えろ!!
I'm not talking to you jackasses! Beat it!
They're just scratches, so I'm okay, Dad...
(てる彦)かすり傷だから
大丈夫だよ 父ちゃ… ぐぉっ！
I'm not Dad! Call me Mom!!
父ちゃんじゃねえ
母ちゃんと呼べ…！
(西郷)てる彦… ｱﾝﾀ 最近➡
Teruhiko, you've been coming home a lot lately all bruised up.
いつも ｹｶﾞして
帰ってくるじゃない｡
What've you been doing? Are you hiding something?
いったい 塾で 何やってるの？
何か隠してんだろ？
D-Don't worry, Mom. I've just been playing samurai...
し… 心配しないでよ 母ちゃん｡
帰りに 友達と
ﾁｬﾝﾊﾞﾗごっこしてるだけだから｡
with my friends on the way home.
じゃあ ﾎﾞｸ 遊びにいってくるね｡
Well, I'm going out to play.
(西郷)ちょっ… 待ちなさい！
Just a minute!
Teruhiko!
てる彦～!!
…ん？
(桂)童｡
Kid.
忘れ物だ｡
You forgot something.
[To all parents: Notice to Parent for Third Annual Visiting Day]
(桂)心配するな
親父殿には見せていない｡
Don't worry. I haven't shown it to your father.
それとも
見せたほうがよかったか？
Should I have?
No... Thanks, auntie.
(てる彦)いや…
ありがとう おねえちゃん｡
(桂)おねえちゃんじゃない｡ 桂だ｡
It's not "auntie." It's Katsura.
Are you sure it's okay?
(桂)いいのか？
親父殿に来てもらわなくて｡
If your father doesn't come?
来てほしいけど…｡
I want him to come, but...
(桂)また ﾊﾞｶにされるのが ｲﾔか？
You don't want to be teased again?
I don't care about that. I'm used to it.
(てる彦)ﾎﾞｸは 別にいいよ
もう 慣れっこだから｡
でも… 父ちゃんが 笑われて
傷つくところは 見たくないんだ｡
But... I don't want to see Dad get laughed at or...hurt.
ﾎﾞｸ 父ちゃんは大好きだよ｡
I love my Dad.
おもしろくて
時々 ちょっと怖いけど…｡
He's fun and can sometimes be a little scary, but...
でも たまに… 父ちゃんが➡
Sometimes, I wish Dad was just a normal dad.
[Closed Till Tonight]
普通の父ちゃんだったら って
思うこともある｡
Mama, you've had too much to drink!
(ﾜｶﾒ)ﾏﾏ ちょっと飲みすぎよ｡
(ｳﾞｧﾈ子)
どうしたっていうの？ 急に｡
What's eating you, all of a sudden?
ほっときなさいよ｡
Leave her alone.
飲みつぶれるまで飲んで
やがて 男は眠るのよ｡
A man drinks until he's wasted, then he can finally sleep.
(ｱｺﾞ美)なに言ってんの 女でしょ！
泣き疲れるまで泣いて➡
Don't you mean "woman"?!
A woman cries until she cries herself to sleep!
女は眠るのよ｡
(ﾜｶﾒ)まったく…｡
Really, Mama, you should stop. Mama and Pako both.
ほどほどにしときなさいよ
ﾏﾏも ﾊﾟｰ子も｡
あの子には
ﾎﾝﾄに 申し訳ないと思ってる｡
I really feel terrible for that boy.
With a father like this, you know...
(西郷)親父が
こんな感じだものね➡
It would be strange if they didn't pick on him.
ﾊﾞｶにされないほうが
おかしいものね｡
なんだ わかってんのか｡
So...you do understand?
That makes this easier...
だったら 話が早えや｡
う～ん… これじゃあ
反社会的勢力の人たちみたいだな｡
Well, now you look like one of those anti-social types.
You need to look more like a hopeless father.
もっと ﾀﾞﾒっぽい親父に…｡
Shall I draw a turd on your forehead?
額に ｳﾝｺでも描いとくか｡
なにやってんだ ﾃﾒｴ｡
What're doing, you...
てる彦が物心つく前に
母親が死んで それからは➡
Teruhiko's mother died before he was old enough to remember.
From then on, I had to be his mother.
私が 母親代わりも
しなきゃいけない って…｡
それが いきすぎて
こうなっちまったけど…｡
I went too far, and ended up like this.
(西郷)私は あの子のために
信念 貫いて やってんだ｡
For that boy's sake, I stuck to my principles.
今まで一度だって
それを後悔したことはないし➡
I've never once regretted my decision, and I don't intend to start now.
これからも するつもりはない｡
Sure, there will be those who laugh at my ugly mug, but my spirit...
まぁ たしかに この醜い姿を見て
笑うﾔﾂもいるけどね｡
この魂だけは…➡
is more beautiful than any man's or woman's.
男よりも女よりも
強く美しいつもりだからさ｡
Yo, so you came.
よぅ 来たかよ｡
弱っちい娘さんよ｡
Weak little girly.
そんな言い方 やめろ｡
ﾎﾞｸは 弱くない｡
Stop saying that! I'm not weak!
(てる彦)その証拠を
お前らに見せてやる！
And I'll prove it.
銀時… ｵﾚは やはり 戻る｡
Gintoki, I'm going back, after all.
あぁ？ なに寝ぼけたこと
言ってんだ ｵﾒｴ｡
Huh? You sure you're awake?
I'm worried about that father and son.
(桂)どうしても
あの親子のことが 気になってな｡
お前 これ以上 ここに い続けたら
本当に 新しい扉 開いちまうぞ｡
If you stay here any longer, you'll really turn into one of them.
化け物は 酔っ払って寝てるし
今しか ﾁｬﾝｽは ねえんだって｡
That freak drunk himself to sleep, so this is our only chance.
逃げるなら いつでもできる｡
だが 今しか やれんこともある｡
You can escape anytime, but now is not the time.
がんばって ﾂﾞﾗ子｡
Good luck, Zurako.
I'll be praying that you don't spend half of your life away here.
人生の半分を ここで
過ごさないよう 祈ってるわ｡
Wait, Pako.
(桂)待て ﾊﾟｰ子｡
ｱﾀﾞﾀﾞﾀﾞﾀﾞ！
Ow-ow-ow-ow-ow!
You're going to rip me in two! Into two new pieces!
ｵﾚが 半分になる！
新しく半分になる!!
んだよ ﾃﾒｴは！ １人で
好きにやりゃいいだろうが！
What is it with you?! Just do what you want by yourself!
(桂)なに言ってんのよ ﾊﾟｰ子｡
私たち２人 ﾂｰﾄｯﾌﾟで➡
What're you saying, Pako?
Haven't we always fought together as the top tag-team?
今まで がんばってきたじゃない！
知るかっ!!
Hell if I know!
まずいﾒｼではあるが 西郷殿には
しばらく食わせてもらった身だろ｡
The food was bad, but we ate at Saigo-dono's table.
恩を返すのは
武士として 当然の道ではないか｡
Isn't it the proper samurai way to return kindness?
武士が ｶﾞｷのｹﾝｶに
首 突っ込むってのか！
You're saying samurai should get involved in a kid's fight?
He's in danger!, What are we gonna do, Yo-chan?
(けんちゃん)よっちゃん
やばいって ｱｲﾂ！
I don't care! It was his idea!
知らないよ ｵﾚは！
ｱｲﾂが 勝手に…！
♪♪～
(よっちゃん)いてててて…！
Ow-ow-ow.
What're you doing? Lemme go!
んだよ 放せよ～！
You guys are gross!
ｷｼｮいんだよ ﾃﾒｴら！
ﾂﾞﾗ子 ｷｼｮいって｡
Zurako, he says you're gross.
What're you talking about? He meant you, Pako.
なに言ってんだ｡
ｷｻﾏのことだぞ ﾊﾟｰ子｡
ｵﾒｴだよ｡ 青白い顔しやがって…｡
外で遊べ｡
He meant you Mr. bleached white face. Play more outdoors.
ｷｻﾏこそ 貧乏丸出しの顔してるぞ｡
What about you? Your face just shouts, "I'm poor!"
盗んだ給食費を 返せ｡
"Give me back the lunch money you stole."
言っとくけど ｵﾚたち
悪くねえからな！
Just so you know, it's not our fault.
ｵﾚたちは 止めたのに
ｱｲﾂ 勝手に…｡
We tried to stop him, but he did it on his own...
要領を得ねえな｡
はっきり言えよ はっきり！
I don't get it. Tell us the details. The details, or I'll shave your head.
ｽﾎﾟｰﾂ刈りにするぞ！
度胸試しだよ！
It was a test of courage.
(けんちゃん)ｵﾚたちの間で
流行ってる度胸試しがあって➡
There's a test of courage that's popular among us kids.
からかってたら ｱｲﾂ ﾎﾝﾄに…｡
When we teased him about it, he took it seriously and...
空き家？
An abandoned house?
It's not an abandoned house. It's in there.
空き家なんかじゃねえよ｡
ここには いるんだ！
こないだも 得体の知れねえ
獣みたいな鳴き声 聞いたし…｡
The other day, we heard a creepy growl... Like it was from a beast.
There's definitely something in there.
(けんちゃん)
なんか 絶対いんだって！
A haunted house, eh?
(桂)化け物屋敷ってﾔﾂか…｡
おい… ﾂﾞﾗ！ ｵﾒｴ すげえな！
Hey, Zura, you're pretty good.
よく こんな狭いとこ… あれ？
How'd you make through such a narrow opening?
Huh? This isn't happening. You can't be serious? No way!
ｳｿ？ あれ？ ﾏｼﾞでか？ ﾏｼﾞでか!?
What're you doing...?
なにをしてるんだ？ ｷｻﾏは｡
I can't move forwards or backwards.
いや… 前にも後ろにも
動かなくなっちゃった｡
(桂)ﾊﾟｰ子… だから
お前は ﾊﾟｰ子なんだ｡
You dumb blonde, that's why they named you Pako.
なんだ この野郎！
ﾊﾟｰやんだったらいいのか ﾃﾒｴ！
What was that, you bastard? I'll "Pa" you!
(桂)ほら 力 抜け｡
ｲﾃﾃﾃﾃ…｡
Come on, relax.
Ow-ow-ow.
ﾀﾞﾒだ… もう ほっといてくれ｡
It's no use. Leave me here. I'll live here from now on!
ｵﾚ もう ここで暮らすわ！
(茂みの物音)
♪♪～
((けんちゃん:ここには いるんだ
得体の知れねえもんが…))
It's in here... Something mysterious...
Teruhiko-kun?
てる彦君？ てる彦君だよな？
You're Teruhiko-kun, aren't you?
Please say you're Teruhiko-kun!
てる彦君だと 言ってくれ！
ﾃﾒｴ… 普通 この状態のｵﾚ
置いてくか!?
You bastard! You'd just leave me here?!
ｷｻﾏ ここに住むと
言っていたではないか｡
You said you wanted to live there.
心配するな｡ すぐ戻ってくる｡
Don't worry. I'll be right back.
ｶｽﾃﾗ 買ってくる｡ ｶｽﾃﾗだから…｡
I'll buy you a castella cake. Castella!
ｶｽﾃﾗなんか 何に使うんだよ！
What would I use a castella cake for?!
ﾂﾞﾗ子～！ 私たち ﾂｰﾄｯﾌﾟで
今までがんばってきたじゃない！
Zurako!
Haven't we always fought together as the top tag-team, up until now?
(桂)知るか！
わかった！ あの あれだ！
Whatever!
I know! That's it!
昔 お前が欲しがってた➡
I'll give you my leather jacket with "Samurai" printed on the back.
背中に ｢侍｣って書いてある
革ｼﾞｬﾝ やるから！
It's what you always wanted!
Who'd wear a tacky jacket like that?!
誰がいるか！
そんなｾﾝｽの悪い革ｼﾞｬﾝ！
(ﾊﾀ皇子)なにをやっとるんだ
おぬしたち｡
What're you humans doing?
(ﾊﾀ皇子)ほうほう…｡
Oh I see...
So a child came in here and hasn't returned since, you say.
(ﾊﾀ)では その子供が
ここに入ったきり 戻ってこんと｡
(ﾊﾀ)おぬしらは
それを捜しにきたわけじゃな？
And you came here to find him?
最近 なにやら子供たちが
この庭に入って➡
Recently we've had a lot of kids coming into the yard and causing mischief.
いたずらしておったからのう｡
See that tree by the annex?
あそこの離れに
木が見えるじゃろう｡
(ﾊﾀ)その木の実を持ち帰れば
立派な侍の証しとか…｡
Kids claim that if they can fetch fruit from that tree, it proves they are a real samurai.
(ﾊﾀ)まぁ 子供らしいといえば
子供らしいが…｡
It's just like children think up such silly things.
So does this yard belong to you, Squirt?
(桂)それでは この庭は
ｷｻﾏのものなのか？
ちっちゃいおっさん｡
(じい)誰に向かって➡
Who the hell are you calling "squirt"?
口 きいとんじゃ ﾜﾚ！
Do you have any idea who this squirt is?
この ちっちゃいおっさんを
どなたと心得る ﾜﾚｪ｡
よさんか じい｡
Stop it, Jii.
Father said that although we come from different planets,
星は違えども 美人には
親切にせよ と➡
父上がおっしゃっていたのを
忘れたか｡
we should always be kind to beautiful women. Have you forgotten that?
Prince, you mustn't be fooled.
(じい)皇子
だまされてはなりませんぞ｡
(じい)なんやかんやで
お父上は➡
After all your father said, he married a homely woman in the end.
結局 ﾌﾞｻｲｸと結婚して
おられるではありませんか｡
Hey! That's my mother you're talking about! My mother!
おい！ それは母上のことか!?
母上のことかぁ!!
Huh? You...
ん？ あれ？ おぬし…｡
(ﾊﾀ)おぬし どこぞで会ったかの？
You... Have we met before?
Heavens no! How sick. Is that the Jomon pickup line?
ｲﾔだぁ ｷﾓ～い！
縄文式のﾅﾝﾊﾟ？
そんなんじゃ 江戸っ娘は➡
You'll never pick up any Edo women that way, baldy.
ひっかからないぞ ﾊｹﾞ 死ねばぁ？
Why don't you just croak.
I see... I thought we met somewhere before, but...
そうか… どこぞで
会った気がするのじゃが｡
美人が困っておるのに
放っておくわけにもいくまい｡
I can't ignore a damsel in distress.
このほうらの人捜し
手伝ってしんぜよう｡
How about we assist them in their search? Eh, Jii?
のう？ じい｡
あっ ｵﾚ ﾊﾟｽ｡
Um, I'll pass. I have a gate-ball match at 4 o'clock.
４時から ｹﾞｰﾄﾎﾞｰﾙ大会 あるから｡
(ﾊﾀ)ｸｿじじい… 地獄のｹﾞｰﾄを
くぐらせてやろうか ｺﾗ！
Old fart. I'll send you through the gate of Hell.
皇子どの ちょっと
伺いたいことが｡
Prince, there's something I'd like to ask you.
子供たちの間で ここに
化け物が棲みついているとの➡
There's a rumor going around the children that a monster lives here.
ｳﾜｻがあるのだが…
何か 心当たりは？
Any idea what that might be?
(うなり声)
What was that? That growl?!
なんだ!? 今の鳴き声！
Something's coming. This time... Something's coming!
(桂)何か来る…
今度こそ 何か来る！
(ﾎﾟﾁの鳴き声)
Pochi, show me some love.
ｵｰｳ ﾎﾟﾁ ﾗﾌﾞﾐｰ｡
化け物とは これのことか？
Is this your monster?
ﾎﾟﾁは 化け物なんかじゃないぞよ｡
Pochi is not a monster.
You're in the yard I prepared for my pet, Pochi.
(ﾊﾀ)ここは 余のﾍﾟｯﾄ
ﾎﾟﾁのために用意した庭でな｡
(ﾊﾀ)空き家だった
武家屋敷を購入して➡
I bought this abandoned samurai mansion, and turned it into Pochi's playground.
ﾎﾟﾁの遊び場にしておる｡
You don't have to worry. Pochi wouldn't hurt a child. Right, Pochi?
心配せずとも ﾎﾟﾁは
子供に危害を加えたりせんわ｡
ねぇ ﾎﾟﾁ｡
Excuse me... May I pet him, too?
すみません ﾎﾞｸも ちょっと
触らせてもらっていいですか？
おい やめとけ！
Hey, don't.
(桂)おぉ… よしよし｡
Good boy, good boy...
なにを おびえている｡
What're you afraid of?
確かに 図体はでかいが
こんなに愛らしい動物が➡
He certainly has a big body, but such a lovable animal wouldn't hurt anyone.
人に危害を加えるわけがなかろう｡
It's an angel. An angel.
天使だ 天使！
(ﾎﾟﾁのうなり声)
おいぃ～！ 天使と悪魔が
同棲してるじゃねえか!!
Hey! It's an angel and a devil rolled into one!
天使と悪魔が
ﾁｰｸﾀﾞﾝｽを 踊ってる！
An angel and devil dancing cheek to cheek!!
ﾎﾟﾁは 辺境の星で発見した
珍種でのう｡
Pochi is an unusual species I found on a remote planet.
下は擬態で これに
寄せつけられたｴｻを➡
The bottom part is fake, right?
Animals lured in by cute faces get eaten by the main part. What a fabulous organism!
上の本体が食らうという➡
たいへんよくできた生物なのじゃ｡
(ﾎﾟﾁの吠え声)
And we're in exactly that situation, aren't we?
まさに 今のｵﾚたちじゃねえか！
大丈夫だって｡
ｻﾗﾐしか食べないもんな ﾎﾟﾁは…｡
It's fine. Pochi only eats salami. Right, precious?
♪♪～
いや これは あれだよ…➡
He's, you know... Just playing. Seriously.
じゃれてるだけだから
いや ﾏｼﾞで｡
No way! He just ate your head nub thingy!
んなわけあるかぁ！
大事な何かを
なくしちまってるじゃねえか！
I'm fine, I tell you. This will grow back.
大丈夫だって…
これ また 生えるから…｡
(ﾎﾟﾁの吠え声)
Look out! This isn't funny!
うぉわっ やばい！ ｼｬﾚにならん!!
Yo-chan, this doesn't sound good. It's going to get those people, too.
よっちゃん… やばいよ
ｱｲﾂらまで！
Yeah...
よっちゃん！ どこ行くの!?
よっちゃん!!
Yo-chan! Where're you going? Yo-chan!
おねえちゃん…
しっかりしてよ おねえちゃん！
...Aunties! Hang in there, Aunties!
よぉ… 元気だったか？ 坊主…｡
Hey... You okay, kid?
You really had us worried. Are you hurt?
(桂)まったく 心配かけおって…
ｹｶﾞはないか？
(てる彦)そのｾﾘﾌ そのまま
ﾊﾞｯﾄで打ち返すよ｡
I could as you the same question!
ﾂﾞﾗ… お前
えらいことになってるぞ｡
Zura, you really are in sorry shape. Where'd you put your body?
体 どこやった？
You're just an exposed head yourself. Namu Amida Butsu.
お前も 生首になってるぞ｡
南無阿弥陀仏 南無阿弥陀仏…｡
Shinpachi! Kagura! Sadaharu! Farewell!
新八 神楽 定春… さようならぁ！
(てる彦)落ち着いてよ！
２人とも➡
Calm down. The two of you have just been buried, that's all.
埋められてるだけだって！
(桂)そうか…｡
I see.
There's nothing to worry about anymore. We've come to save you.
もう 心配はいらん｡ 助けにきた｡
っていうか 助けてくれ｡
Or should I say, please save us.
(てる彦)なにしに来たんだよ
おねえちゃん…｡
Why did you come here, aunties?
Never mind that. We're glad you're safe.
それより お前 よく無事だったな｡
うん… ﾎﾞｸ ずっと
木の上に隠れてたんだ｡
Yeah. I was hiding up in a tree the whole time.
(てる彦)降りるに
降りられなくなって 困ってたら➡
I didn't dare come down. Then I saw you being carried off by that thing.
おねえちゃんたちが ｱｲﾂに
運ばれてきて…｡
That Pochi, he learned a new trick. How sweet.
ﾎﾟﾁめ… こんな遊びを覚えおって
ういﾔﾂじゃ｡
皇子… ﾎﾟﾁはね
ｴｻを保管するとき➡
Prince, Pochi does this when he wants to store his food.
こうして 埋める習性が
あるのです｡
(じい)どうしてくれんだよ
ﾊﾞｶ皇子！
What're you going to do about this, you idiot prince?!
(じい)ｵﾚの人生も ｹﾞｰﾄﾎﾞｰﾙ大会も
すべてﾊﾟｰだ！
My life and my gate-ball match are over!
(ﾊﾀ)うるせえ ｸｿじじい！
Shut up, you old fart!
If we get out of this, I'm definitely firing you!
(ﾊﾀ)ここ出たら 絶対
ｸﾋﾞにしてやっからな！
Go right ahead.
(じい)やってみろよ！
We're all going to die here anyway.
(じいや)どうせ みんな
ここで死ぬんだよ ﾋｯﾋｯﾋ…｡
(てる彦)みんな ごめん…｡
I'm sorry, everybody. It's my fault this happened...
(てる彦)ﾎﾞｸのせいで こんなことに
なっちゃって…｡
なにやってんだろ ﾎﾞｸ…｡
What have I done?
こんな たくさんの人に
迷惑かけて…｡
I've caused so much trouble for everyone...
なにが 弱くない証拠
見せてやる だよ…｡
I wanted to somehow prove that I wasn't weak.
(てる彦)でも… やっぱり
父ちゃんのこと➡
But...
I was so angry that everyone made fun of Dad.
ﾊﾞｶにされるのが 悔しくて…｡
Dad is the way he is, but I know that he has a spirit that's stronger and purer than anyone.
(てる彦)父ちゃんは
あんなだけど➡
誰よりも強くて きれいな心を
もってることを➡
ﾎﾞｸは 知ってる…｡
But no one sees that. They don't even try.
(てる彦)でも 誰も そんなの
見えないし 見ようとしない…｡
(てる彦)悔しい…｡
It makes me so angry...
I'm... so frustrated.
ﾎﾞｸ 悔しいよ…｡
お前…｡
(ﾎﾟﾁのうなり声)
You...
He's coming...
(ﾊﾀ)きっ 来た～！
ﾎﾟﾁ～！ 食べるなら じいにせい！
Pochi, if you have to eat, then eat Jii!
余は 脂ばっかりで 体に悪いぞ！
I'm all fat and bad for your health!
なに言ってんだぁ！
じいは 食べたら➡
What're you saying?!
If you eat me, my bones will stick in your throat for sure! Eat the prince!
骨 刺さるぞ これ絶対！
皇子にしとけ!!
(ﾎﾟﾁのうなり声)
Hey! Hey! He's coming this way!
おいおい こっち来てんぞ！
That's enough! Forget about us and just run away!
もういい！ ｵﾚたちはいいから
お前だけでも 逃げろ！
ﾃﾒｴまで おっちぬぞ！
おい 聞いてんのか!!
You'll be killed, too! Hey! Are you listening?!
うるさい！ ﾎﾞｸは強いんだ!!
絶対 逃げない！
Shut up! I'm strong! I won't run away!
そんなこと言ってる場合か！
早く 逃げろ!!
This is no time to say such things! Hurry!
Runnnn!!
(ﾎﾟﾁのうなり声)
ﾎﾞｸは強い だって…？
You are strong...
We already knew that!
(桂/銀時)知ってるよ
んなこたぁ！
ｵﾒｴも ｵﾒｴの父ちゃんも➡
You and your dad are both men of strong spirit.
十分 魂の強え男だ｡
誰も見てくれねえって？
ﾊﾞｶ言うな！
You think nobody can see that? Don't be stupid.
見えてるﾔﾂには 見えてるよ
んなもん！
Those who can see that, see it.
少なくとも ここに
２人いることだけは 覚えておけ｡
At the very least, there are two right here who can see it. Remember that.
おねえちゃん…｡
Auntie...
As if you would know.
(西郷)ﾌﾝ… 生意気 言いやがって｡
くぅあぁ～っ!!
♪♪～
(てる彦)かっ… 母ちゃん！
M-Mom!
♪♪～
うおぉりゃあぁ～っ！
うおぉりゃあぁ～っ!!
♪♪～
思い出したぞ！
I remember now...
Back during the Amanto invasion,
(桂)天人襲来の折 白ﾌﾝ一丁で
敵の戦艦に乗り込み➡
there was a man who wore nothing but a white loincloth when he stormed the enemy battleship.
白いﾌﾝﾄﾞｼが 敵の血で
真っ赤に染まるまで➡
He fought until that white loincloth was stained crimson with the blood of the enemy.
暴れまわった 伝説の男…➡
His exploits are legend.
鬼神 西郷 特盛！
The Demon, Tokumori Saigo!
♪♪～
He's our great Senpai.
(桂)ｵﾚたちの 大先輩に
あたる人だ…｡
M-Mom... I'm sorry. I...
かっ… 母ちゃん ごめん…｡
Idiot! Right now, call me Dad.
ﾊﾞｶ野郎… 今は 父ちゃんと呼べ｡
Hey.
(西郷)おい… ﾃﾒｴらは ｸﾋﾞだ｡
You two are fired.
いつまでたっても
踊りは覚えねえし➡
You still can't dance, no matter how much you practice.
ﾛｸに 役にたたねえ｡
If you ever call us freaks again, I won't go easy on you, you hear?!
今度 私らを
化け物なんて言ったら➡
承知しねえからな｡
それから…｡
And one other thing...
(西郷)なんかあったら
いつでも 店に遊びにきな｡
If you are ever feeling frisky, come visit the club for a good time.
たっぷり ｻｰﾋﾞｽするわよ｡
We'll treat you real special.
He scares me.
怖いよ…｡
どうやら➡
Looks like we didn't need to worry.
いらぬ心配を したようだな｡
(桂)ﾔﾂらも 侍と変わらんな｡
They're no different than samurai. They have a path of their own to follow.
(桂)立派な求道者だよ…｡
My Father-Mother.
(てる彦)｢ﾎﾞｸの お父さんお母さん｡
ﾎﾞｸのお母さんは お母さんですが
お父さんでもあります｡
My mother is my mother, but she's also my father.
というか 本当は
お父さんなんだけど➡
Actually, she's my father, but she's my mother.
お母さんなんです｡
Mother has a lot of ladies around her,
お母さんの周りには
おねえさんが いっぱいいて➡
みんな 自分を蝶と
言い張りますが➡
who call themselves butterflies, but they're really more like moths.
どっちかというと 蛾です｡
でも みんな いい人ばっかりで➡
But they're all good people.
心は どんな人たちよりも
きれいだと➡
I think their spirits are purer than anyone else's.
ﾎﾞｸは思います｣
Mom, everyone. I hope you remain wonderful moths forever.
｢お母さん みんな いつまでも➡
ｽﾃｷな蛾でいてください｡
そんなみんなが ﾎﾞｸは大好きです｡
I love you all. The end.
おわり｣
I really should stop coming to Earth.
ﾎﾝﾄ… 地球 来んの やめよ…｡
["Actually, you did want this leather jacket, didn't you?"]
["Hmph! I just accepted it for your sake."]
[Preview]
Gin-san, Gin-san!
Gin Tama's been renewed for a third season!
Really?
We have to celebrate!
Shall we splurge on sukiyaki, then?
The next episode: "A Shared Soup Pot is a Microcosm of Life."